第一章
話說從前…
納粹鐵蹄下的法國
1941年
入屋，關門
茱莉，倒水給我洗面
然後跟姐妹入屋
倒了，爸爸
謝謝
入屋去吧
不要跑
拉柏提的農莊？
我是拉柏提
你好，拉柏提先生
黨衛軍的蘭達上校
請問貴幹？
可不可以進入府上
談幾句？
當然可以，請
蘭達上校，我的女兒
黨衛軍的蘭達上校
小姐
幸會
關於令千金的傳聞，原來是實情
Monsieur Lapadite
果然一位比一位俏麗
過獎
請
請坐
Suzanne
蘇珊，給上校斟酒
不用客氣
多謝好意，拉柏提先生
這是乳牛場，大概有牛奶吧？
有
我希望喝牛奶
好吧
茱莉，關窗好嗎？
謝謝
向你的家人、你的乳牛
衷心讚賞
謝謝
請坐近來
好吧
拉柏提先生
這件事，我想同你私下談
所以我吩咐部下外面等
三位千金不介意稍稍迴避吧？
說得對
綽洛，你們出去好嗎？
上校有話跟我說
拉柏提先生
我的法語非常有限
再講下去，只會出醜
聽說你英語流利
對
我剛巧也講得通
我們改用英語交談
好不好？
請隨便
我很熟悉你一家
While I'm very familiar with you and your family,
你熟不熟悉我？
I have no way of knowing if you are familiar with who I am.
聽過我嗎？
Are you aware of my existence?
﹣聽過﹣好
-Yes. -This is good.
我來法國做甚麼，知道嗎？
Now, are you aware of the job I've been ordered to carry out in France?
知道
Yes.
說來聽
Please tell me what you've heard.
聽說
I've heard that the Fuhrer has put you in charge of rounding up the Jews left in France.
還有些猶太人匿藏在法國內
元首要你搜捕他們
who are either hiding or passing for Gentile.
非常準確
The Fuhrer couldn't have said better himself.
很歡迎你光臨
But the meaning of your visit,
但還不明白可以怎樣效勞
pleasant though it is, is mysterious to me.
九個月前，貴軍來搜屋
The Germans looked through my house nine months ago for hiding Jews
搜不出甚麼
and found nothing.
我知道
I'm aware of that.
我閱讀過報告
I've read the reports of this area.
新官上任三把火
But like any enterprise, when under new management,
有些事情重覆處理
there is always a slight duplication of efforts,
是在所難免
most of it being a complete waste of time, but needs to be done nevertheless.
我想問幾句
I just have a few questions, Monsieur Lapadite.
你能夠回答的話
If you can assist me with answers,
我們就結束你家的調查
my department can close the file on your family.
我軍進駐之前本區有四戶猶太人家
Now,
before the occupation, there were four Jewish families in this area,
都是你那樣的乳牛農民
all dairy farmers like yourself.
分別姓狄、姓盧、姓陸
Doleracs, Rollins, the Loveitts
姓戴
and the Dreyfuses.
對不對？
Is that correct?
據我所知
To my knowledge,
猶裔的乳牛農民，都是這幾戶
those were the Jewish families among the dairy farmers.
上校閣下介意我抽煙斗嗎？
Herr Colonel, would it disturb you if I smoked my pipe?
隨便
Please, Monsieur Lapadite,
這是你家，不用客氣
this is your house, make yourself comfortable.
根據記錄
Now, according to these papers,
本區猶太人下落，全部已知
all the Jewish families in this area have been accounted for
除了姓戴一家外
except the Dreyfuses.
去年，他們似乎消失了
Somewhere in the last year it would appear they've vanished.
不是逃脫
Which leads me to the conclusion that they've either made good their escape
就是有人成功把他們窩藏
or someone is very successfully hiding them.
你有沒有聽過戴家的消息？
What have you heard about the Dreyfuses, Monsieur Lapadite?
﹣只是傳聞﹣我喜歡傳聞！
-Only rumors. -I love rumors!
事實可以令人無所適從
Facts could be so misleading,
但傳聞即使是假，也會有所啟示
where rumors, true or false, are often revealing.
拉柏提先生
So, Monsieur Lapadite,
你聽到戴家甚麼傳聞？
what rumors have you heard regarding the Dreyfuses?
再次聲明，只是傳聞
Again, this is just a rumor,
聽說姓戴一家去了西班牙
but we heard the Dreyfuses had made their way into Spain.
即是逃脫了？
So, the rumors you've heard have been of escape?
對
Yes.
你可不可以核實一下
Having never met the Dreyfuses,
would you prefer for me the exact members of the household and their names?
戴家各人的身份名字？
一共五人
There were five of them.
父親雅各
The father, Jacob.
妻子瑪琳
Wife, Miram.
妻舅卜
And her brother, Bob.
卜幾歲？
How old is Bob?
三十、三十一
Thirty, 31 .
繼續
Continue.
兒女
And the children,
阿莫斯
Amos
蘇珊娜
and Shosanna.
兒女年歲
Ages of the children?
阿莫斯九、十歲
Amos was nine or 10.
蘇珊娜阿莫斯九、十歲
﹣蘇珊娜呢？﹣蘇珊娜
And Shosanna?
And Shosanna was
十八、十九不很肯定
18 or 19. I'm not really sure.
那就問完了
Well, I guess that should do it.
臨別可以再喝杯美味的牛奶嗎？
However, before I go, could I have another glass of your delicious milk?
當然可以
But of course.
拉柏提先生
Monsieur Lapadite,
法國人給我起了綽號，知嗎？
are you aware of the nickname the people of France have given me?
我不理會這些事
I have no interest in such things.
不過你聽過？
But you are aware of what they call me.
聽過
I'm aware.
甚麼綽號？
What are you aware of?
﹣猶太獵手﹣對極
That they call you "The Jew Hunter."
Precisely.
你提起也怕，也難怪
I understand your trepidation in repeating it.
布拉格人叫希德烈做劊子手
Heydrich apparently hates the moniker the good people of Prague have bestowed on him.
希德烈很抗拒
為甚麼抗拒？我也莫名其妙
Actually, why he would hate the name "the Hangman" is baffling to me.
他付出一番努力，實至名歸
It would appear he has done everything in his power to earn it.
我卻喜愛我的綽號
Now I, on the other hand, love my unofficial title
我自覺當之無愧
precisely because I've earned it.
捕獵猶太人的能力
The feature that makes me such an effective hunter of the Jews is,
我超越一般德軍
as opposed to most German soldiers,
我摸透猶太人心態
I can think like a Jew
德軍只有德國人心態
where they can only think like a German.
更準確而言，只有德軍心態
More precisely, a German soldier.
以動物來作比擬吧
Now, if one were to determine what attribute the German people share with a beast,
德國人，我認為像鷹
it would be the cunning and the predatory instinct of a hawk.
而猶太人呢
But if one were to determine what attributes the Jews share with a beast,
我認為像鼠
it would be that of the rat.
元首與戈培爾也當他們做老鼠
The Fuhrer and Goebbels' propaganda have said pretty much the same thing.
不過，我不認為
But where our conclusions differ,
把猶太人當做老鼠是侮辱
is I don't consider the comparison an insult.
想想老鼠的世界吧
Consider for a moment the world a rat lives in.
四面楚歌
It's a hostile world, indeed.
過街老鼠
If a rat were to scamper through your front door, right now,
你會不會打？
would you greet it with hostility?
大概會
I suppose I would.
老鼠有甚麼得罪你？
Has a rat ever done anything to you to create this animosity you feel toward them?
老鼠傳播疾病、咬人
Rats spread disease. They bite people.
傳播淋巴腺鼠疫，很久以前了
Rats were the cause of the bubonic plague, but that's some time ago.
老鼠可以傳播
I propose to you any disease a rat could spread, a squirrel could equally carry.
松鼠也可以
同意嗎？
Would you agree?
Right.
但你不打過街松鼠
Yet, I assume you don't share the same animosity with squirrels that you do with rats, do you?
﹣卻打過街老鼠，對嗎？﹣對
No.
兩者都是齧齒目動物
Yet, they're both rodents, are they not?
尾巴不同，模樣大同小異
And except for the tail, they even rather look alike, don't they?
上校見解獨到
It's an interesting thought, Herr Colonel.
無論我見解怎樣獨到
However interesting as the thought may be,
也改變不到你的感覺
it makes not one bit of difference to how you feel.
現在有老鼠走進來
If a rat were to walk in here, right now, as I'm talking
你會不會用美味牛奶招待？
would you greet it with a saucer of your delicious milk?
多數不會
Probably not.
我也認為不會
I didn't think so.
你不喜歡老鼠
You don't like them.
你也不明白為甚麼不喜歡
You don't really know why you don't like them.
總之一見反感
All you know is you find them repulsive.
言歸正傳
Consequently, a German soldier conducts a search of a house suspected of hiding Jews.
德軍入屋搜猶太人，會搜哪處？
鷹會搜哪處？
Where does the hawk look?
會搜穀倉，搜閣樓，搜地窖
He looks in the barn, he looks in the attic, he looks in the cellar,
凡是鷹會匿躲的地方
he looks everywhere he would hide.
鷹都會搜
But there are so many places it would never occur to a hawk to hide.
但鼠會匿躲的地方，鷹卻想不到元首召我出阿爾卑斯山…
However, the reason the Fuhrer has brought me off my Alps in Austria
派我來法國，因為我想得到
and placed me in French cow country today is because it does occur to me.
因為我知道捨棄尊嚴的人
Because I'm aware what tremendous feats human beings are capable of
無所不為
once they abandon dignity.
我也可以抽煙斗嗎？
May I smoke my pipe as well?
隨便，不要客氣
Please, Herr Colonel, make yourself at home.
現在我職責在身
Now, my job dictates
不得不下令部屬
that I must have my men enter your home
進來徹底搜查
and conduct a thorough search
為了可以證實你一家清白
before I can officially cross your family's name off my list.
這次搜查必會搜出罪證
And if there are any irregularities to be found, rest assured they will be.
除非你肯坦白
That is unless you have something to tell me
省卻我麻煩
that makes the conducting of a search unnecessary.
你肯坦白
I might add, also, that any information
協助我的話不僅不會受罰
that makes the performance of my duty easier will not be met with punishment.
而且會到獎賞
Actually, quite the contrary. It will be met with reward.
獎賞是
And that reward will be, your family will cease to be harassed in any way
佔領期間
我們絕不會騷擾你一家
by the German military during the rest of our occupation of your country.
有沒有窩藏敵人？
You're sheltering enemies of the state, are you not?
有
Yes.
地板下，是不是？
You're sheltering them underneath your floorboards, aren't you?
是
Yes.
指出窩藏地點
Point out to me the areas where they're hiding.
既然沒有動靜
Since I haven't heard any disturbance,
他們大概在聽，但聽不懂英語
I assume, while they're listening, they don't speak English.
對
Yes.
我改說法語，你陪我做戲做下去
I'm going to switch back to French now, and I want you to follow my masquerade. Is that clear?
明白？
明白
Yes.
拉柏提先生
多謝你的牛奶
你的款待
事情到此為止
各位小姐
感謝你們抽空
不再打擾了
先生
小姐
就此告辭
請請
那女兒
It's the girl.
後會有期蘇珊娜！
Au revoir, Shosanna!
第二章
辣手兵團
立正！
ALDO: Ten-hut!
我是艾杜中尉
My name is Lieutenant Aldo Raine.
我要組織一小隊，要八個人
And I'm putting together a special team, and I need me eight soldiers.
八個猶太裔美軍
Eight Jewish American soldiers.
你們或者聽過聯軍就快大反攻
Now, you all might've heard rumors about the armada happening soon.
我們是先頭部隊
Well, we'll be leaving a little earlier.
我們會空降法國，扮做平民
We're going to be dropped into France dressed as civilians.
在敵區內
Once we're in enemy territory,
打游擊，施奇襲
as a bushwhacking guerrilla army,
我們只做一事，獨沽一味
we're going to be doing one thing and one thing only.
殺納粹
Killing Nazis.
我不知你們作何打算
I don't know about you all, but
不過，我從大煙山下山
I sure as hell didn't come down from the goddamn Smoky Mountains,
航行五千浬，轉戰西西里
cross 5,000 miles of water, fight my way through half of Sicily
深入敵陣，不是為了感化納粹
and jump out of a fucking airplane to teach the Nazis lessons in humanity.
納粹沒有人性
Nazi ain't got no humanity.
他們仇恨猶太人，嗜血成狂
They're the foot soldiers of a Jew-hating, mass-murdering maniac
必須消滅
and they need to be destroyed.
凡是身穿納粹制服的雜種
That's why any and every son of a bitch we find wearing a Nazi uniform,
我們一見就殺
they're going to die.
我是原野奇人占貝加的直系子孫
Now, I'm the direct descendent of the mountain man Jim Bridger.
意思是我有印第安血統
That means I got a little Indian in me.
我們會繼承阿帕奇族的戰鬥作風
And our battle plan will be that of an Apache resistance.
我們會絕不手軟
We will be cruel to the Germans.
德軍會領教我們手段
And through our cruelty, they will know who we are.
我們會把他們斬殺得
And they will find the evidence of our cruelty
四肢殘缺，肚破腸流
in the disemboweled, dismembered
德軍會見識自己的弟兄
and disfigured bodies of their brothers we leave behind us.
怎樣被我們修理
And the German won't be able to help themselves
怎樣體無完膚
but imagine the cruelty their brothers endured at our hands,
怎樣不似人形
and our boot heels and the edge of our knives.
德軍會聞風喪膽
And the German will be sickened by us.
德軍所談的會是我們
And the German will talk about us.
所怕的是我們
And the German will fear us.
所夢的是我們
And when the German closes their eyes at night
他們虧心事做盡
and they're tortured by their subconscious for the evil they have done,
我們找上門，要他們膽戰心驚
it will be with thoughts of us that they are tortured with.
好不好？
Sound good?
好，上尉
-ALL: Yes, sir! -Yes, sir!
啱聽
That's what I like to hear.
先此聲明，你們這班準戰士
But I got a word of warning for all you would-be warriors.
既然做我部下，就欠我一筆債
When you join my command, you take on debit.
你們人人欠我一筆債
A debit you owe me, personally.
你們人人欠我一百副納粹頭皮
Each and every man under my command owes me 100 Nazi scalps.
我要頭皮
And I want my scalps.
你們每人要割下一百副納粹頭皮，獻給我
And all y'all will get me 100 Nazi scalps taken from the heads of 100 dead Nazis.
你們要一直割，割到死為止
Or you will die trying!
不！
猶太豬玀，豈有此理！
把我的軍人，當烏蠅來拍！
人人嚇到神不守舍疑神疑鬼！
那個
專用棍打人的猶太佬！
軍人叫他做“猶太神熊”
說他有法術！
只是軍中的瘋言瘋語
沒有人相信“猶太神熊”有法術
沒有人相信？
他們神出鬼沒
我們處處撲個空
你想證實他們有血有肉？
那就抓來給我！
我要把他們赤條條倒吊鐵塔頂！
然後把屍體扔落溝渠
請巴黎老鼠吃九大簋！
卡拉斯！
是，元首！
我要向全體德軍下命令
禁止再提“猶太神熊”這外號
是，元首！
元首依然接見士兵布茲嗎？
布茲？
你想接見的士兵
他那小組遭艾杜中尉伏擊
死剩他一個
我的確想見，多謝提醒
叫他進來
只剩歷曼上士路得域、我三個
對方一人監視，其餘割頭皮
辣手兵團
賀舒堡
Hey, Hirschberg.
叫那德軍上士來
Send that Kraut sarge over.
你，走
HlRSCHBERG: You. Go.
歷曼上士
Sergeant Werner Rachtman.
我是艾杜中尉，幸會
Lieutenant Aldo Raine. Pleased to meet you.
懂得坐嗎？潤腸
You know what "sit down" means, Werner?
﹣懂﹣那就坐下吧
-Yes. -Then sit down.
懂英語？
How is your English, Werner?
有必要的話，我們有翻譯
Because if need be, we got a couple of fellows who can translate.
那個域基
Wicki here,
奧地利的猶太人，逃出慕尼黑
an Austrian-Jew, got the fuck out of Munich while the getting was good.
做了美國人，當了美國兵現在回來報答你們
Became American, got drafted, come back to give y'all what for.
另一個，你或者熟悉
Another one up there you might be familiar with.
史提傑茲上士
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz.
聽過大名？
Heard of him?
德軍個個都聽過史提傑茲
Everybody in the German Army has heard of Hugo Stiglitz.
史提傑茲
為甚麼史提傑茲出名？原因簡單
MALE NARRATOR.; The reason for Hugo Stiglitz's celebrity among German soldiers is simple.
他本來是德軍卻殺死13名蓋世太保
As a German-enlisted man, he killed 13 Gestapo officers.
司令部不立即槍斃
Instead of putting him up against a wall,
打算先押解回柏林
the High Command decided to send him back to Berlin
然後殺雞儆猴
to be made an example of.
不消說辣手兵團收到風聲
Needless to say, once the Basterds heard about him,
他去不成柏林
he never got there.
史提傑茲上士？
Sergeant Hugo Stiglitz?
艾杜中尉，我們是辣手兵團
Lieutenant Aldo Raine. These are the Basterds.
有沒有聽過？
Ever heard of us?
我們很欣賞你
We just want to say we're a big fan of your work.
你很有殺納粹的天份
When it comes to killing Nazis,
我是慧眼識納粹殺手
I think you show great talent.
美中不足的是，你依然是業餘
And I pride myself for having an eye for that kind of talent.
想不想精益求精
But your status as a Nazi killer is still amateur.
升級做專業？
We all come here to see if you want to go pro.
你認得我們吧？
Can I assume you know who we are?
你是生番艾杜
You're Aldo the Apache.
那麼，你必也知道
Werner, if you heard of us,
我們的生意是專殺納粹份子
you probably heard we ain't in the prisoner-taking business.
並且不留活口，而且生意興隆
We in the killing Nazi business, and, cousin, business is a-booming.
對
HlRSCHBERG:(LAUGHlNG) Oh, yeah.
現在只有兩條路
Now, that leaves two ways we can play this out.
殺你、放你
Either kill you or let you go.
你走不走得出這個坑
Whether or not you're going to leave this ditch alive
完全由你自己決定
depends entirely on you.
前面，有個果園
Up the road a piece, there's an orchard.
有隊德軍在附近佈防
Besides you, we know there's another Kraut patrol fucking around here somewhere.
假如我們進入果園
If that patrol were to have any crack shots,
就變成槍靶
that orchard would be a goddamn sniper's delight.
你想再吃到家鄉香腸的話
So if you ever want to eat a sauerkraut sandwich again,
就要點出他們的位置
you got to show me on this here map where they are.
要告訴我有幾多人
You got to tell me how many they are
and you got to tell me what kind of artillery they're carrying with them.
攜帶甚麼槍炮
你不認為我會透露情報出賣同胞吧？
You can't expect me to divulge information that would put German lives in danger.
潤腸，你錯了，我認為你會
Well, now, Werner, that's where you're wrong, because that's exactly what I expect.
我要知道埋伏的德軍情況
I need to know about Germans hiding in trees.
你要告訴我立即告訴我
And you need to tell me. And you need to tell me right now.
你要指出
Now, just take that finger of yours
德軍隱藏的位置
and point out on this here map where this party is being held,
有幾多人攜帶幾多架罉
how many is coming and what they brought to play with.
不好意思，我要拒絕
I respectfully refuse, sir.
聽到嗎？
Hear that?
聽到
Yes.
那是當奴威茲上士
That's Sergeant Donny Donowitz.
你比較熟悉他的綽號
You might know him better by his nickname.
猶太神熊
The Bear Jew.
你聽過生番艾杜必定也聽過猶太神熊
Now, if you heard of Aldo the Apache, you got to have heard about The Bear Jew.
﹣我聽過猶太神熊﹣聽過他甚麼？
-I heard of The Bear Jew. -What did you hear?
專扑德軍
Beats German soldiers with a club.
專門用棒球棍扑頭殼
He bashes their brains in with a baseball bat, what he does.
潤腸，問你最後一次
And, Werner, I'm going to ask you one last goddamn time,
你依然不好意思地拒絕
and if you still respectfully refuse, I'm calling The Bear Jew over.
我叫猶太神熊來
He's going to take that big bat of his,
他會掄起大棍扑你扑成屎醬
and he's going to beat your ass to death with it.
現在用你隻德國豬手
Now, take your Wiener-schnitzel-licking finger,
點出我所要的位置
and point out on this map what I want to know.
仆街啦你
Fuck you.
猶太狗
And your Jew dogs.
其實你那樣說，我們求之不得
Actually, Werner, we're all tickled to hear you say that.
這處沒有電影看
Quite frankly, watching Donny beat Nazis to death
只好看阿當打納粹阿當！
is the closest we ever get to going to the movies. Donny!
怎樣？
DONNY: Yeah?
有件德軍要為國捐軀
Got us a German here who wants to die for country.
成全他吧
Oblige him.
殺猶太人得來？
Did you get that for killing Jews?
英勇作戰
Bravery.
阿當！
BASTERD 1 : Oh, no!
BASTERD 2: Oh, no!
Donny!
BASTERD: Yeah, Donny!
我是你，我會瀨屎
About now I'd be shitting my pants if I was you.
威廉斯一擊把球擊出場外！
Teddy Fucking Williams knocks it out of the park!
觀眾彈起來拍爛手掌！
Fenway Park is on its feet for Teddy Fucking Ballgame!
完美的全壘打！
He went yard on that one, on to fucking Lansdowne Street!
你！
You!
好心你，賀舒堡！
Damn it, Hirschberg!
阿當，押他來，要活人！
Donny, bring that other one over here. Alive!
上去！輪到你！
Get the fuck up! Batter up. You're on deck!
兩下，我扑你，你仆地
Two hits. I hit you, you hit the ground.
懂英語？
English?
域基
ALDO: Wicki.
問他要不要命
Ask him if he wants to live.
叫他指出德軍位置
Tell him to point out on this map the German position.
有幾多德軍？
Ask him how many Germans.
12個左右
Around about 1 2.
甚麼槍炮？
What kind of artillery?
你怎樣逃過大難？
他們放我走
你回去，把經過
Now, when you report what happened here,
照實報告的話，會槍斃
you can't tell them you told us what you told us. They'll shoot you.
你對他們解釋，我們網開一面放你走
They're going to want to know why you so special, we let you live.
是要你告訴其他德軍
So tell them, we let you live...
so you could spread the word through the ranks what's going to happen to every Nazi we find.
我們怎樣收拾納粹份子
不准你說，一個字也不准說
你們中伏，你逃出！
只此而已！
是，元首
他們有沒有照例打記號？
有，元首
你有命回家，會做甚麼？
Now that you've survived the war, when you get home, what you going to do?
我會擁抱媽媽，熱烈擁抱
他會擁抱他媽
WlCKl: He's going to hug his mother.
多有孝心
Well, ain't that nice?
問他會不會脫軍服？
Ask if he's going to take off his uniform.
不止會脫，而且會燒
他會燒軍服
WlCKl: He's going to burn it.
不出所料，但我們反對
Yeah, that's what we thought. We don't like that.
納粹應該穿軍服，打正招牌
See, we like our Nazis in uniforms. That way you can spot them.
方便辨認
just like that.
你脫軍服，誰知你是納粹？
But you take off that uniform, ain't nobody going to know you's a Nazi.
我們反對脫
And that don't sit well with us.
所以我要給你脫不掉的記認
So I'm going to give you a little something you can't take off.
You know, Lieutenant, you're getting pretty good at that.
上尉，你手法純熟
想做大師，只靠一個字
You know how you get to Carnegie Hall, don't you?
練習
Practice.
第三章
巴黎的德國之夜
1944年
6月
電影院
戴蘇珊娜家人慘死四年後
明天上映甚麼？
連達的電影節
我喜歡連達多過卓別靈
但連達拍不出《孤兒流浪記》
《孤兒》那場追逐，拍得精彩
我很喜愛你們的戲院
多謝
你的？
我是不是老闆？
對
是
這樣年輕就有戲院？
我叔嬸的遺產
多謝你舉辦德國之夜
不得不舉辦
但不用客氣
我愛看瑞芬舒丹鏡頭下的山脈
尤其是那齣《帕魯峰》
你欣賞瑞芬舒丹真好
我對瑞芬舒丹
說不上是欣賞
但你欣賞柏布斯導演吧
所以你在牌板上
掛上他姓名
我們法國人尊重導演
即使是德國導演
對
感謝你幫忙，再見
你還未掛完
明早才掛
請問貴姓？
你想檢查我文件？
艾曼妞美慕
很漂亮的名字
過獎
文件檢查完？
小姐，容我自我介紹
法德烈梭拉
大家是影迷聊聊天是樂事
晚安，小姐
再見
你好，小姐
可以坐嗎？
法德烈…
你記得我名字？
記得
你似乎是個和氣的人
謝謝
不用客氣
請不要再來滋擾
抱歉，小姐
我不是故意滋擾
我只想交朋友
我不想做你朋友
為甚麼？
不要明知故問
我不只是軍人
你是軍人
你急於結交法國女友
可以去維希區
你是誰？
我只是軍人
你不是普通德軍
你是某人的兒子？
德軍大多有父親
你很有福氣，男友是戰爭英雄
小姐不是我女友
可以寫《親愛的巴貝》嗎？
原來你是戰爭英雄
做了甚麼？
我曾經單獨在鐘樓上守城
我、子彈千發、雀巢
敵軍有三百名
雀巢？
狙擊手叫鐘樓做雀巢
居高臨下，360度視野
非常有利狙擊
你殺了幾多人？
68個
第一日
150個
第二日
32個，第三日
第四日，敵軍撤退
我的事蹟在國內廣泛報道
於是人人都認得我
叫我做無敵上士
或者會把你拍成電影
戈培爾宣傳部長已經拍了
片名是《國家光榮》
我奉命自己飾演自己
片已經拍完
戈培爾認為這齣戲會是他傑作
而我會做銀幕英雄
《國家光榮》是你事蹟？
由你主演？
對
滑稽吧？
祝電影順利，祝戈培爾同你好運
拜拜！
﹣要幫手嗎？﹣不用了
我在士多房
得
美慕小姐？
甚麼事？
你的戲院？
是
下來！
麻煩你
甚麼事？我想知道
她想知道
滾上車去
美國體育健將，大都是奴隸後代
美國奧運金牌，用黑人汗水換取
第三帝國第二號人物戈培爾
來得好
感謝你接受邀請
邀請？
你口中那位小姐？
對，戈培爾博士
艾曼妞，我來介紹
這位是宣傳部長
德國影壇的統帥
我既然是演員他也是我上司，戈培爾博士
原來你就是美慕小姐
戈培爾博士的法語翻譯員
方茜嘉小姐
你好
你見過少校
我是蓋世太保的哈斯唐少校
幸會
容許我
坐下
香檳相當不錯，嚐嚐
不得不說，我有點怪責你
我來到法國
想同我的電影明星吃午餐
想不到
他在巴黎當了大紅人
要抽空才見得到我
從來只有人等我我不等人
除了元首
與大兵梭拉
終於等到這兵哥賞面
他談你、談你戲院，談個不停
美慕小姐，現在言歸正傳
戈培爾博士
我還未告訴她
除非是笨蛋，否則已經猜到
她畢竟打理一家戲院
方茜嘉，告訴她
兵哥梭拉花了一小時
設法游說戈培爾博士
把電影的首映禮
改在你的戲院舉行
甚麼？
我正打算告訴她
不好意思，你當然打算告訴她
甚麼事？
兵哥想親自告訴小姐
廢話！
我還未發問，他告訴甚麼？
記低：“我未同意改變首映場地”
明白
你有歌劇廂座嗎？
有
幾多個？
兩個
多幾個會比較好
院內有幾多座位？
比麗斯戲院少400
可是，戈培爾博士
那並不是壞處
你認為法國中產人士虛偽
討厭接見他們
少座位，少接待
他們要爭位也無位可爭
我們索性排除法國人
德國之夜，屬於德國人
只是為你、為我
為德軍、為總司令
為親友而舉行
看劇情而感動
只有那些人才應該入場
你的演講技巧有進步
我製造出一個魔頭
一個有歪理的魔頭
當完兵，可以從政
士兵
雖然我願意遷就你
但要去戲院看看戲才下決定
你今晚暫停營業只放映電影給我看
有甚麼德國片？
蘭達，你在這裡
這位是黨衛軍的蘭達上校
他負責首映的保安
幸會，小姐
後會有期，蘇珊娜！
HANS: Au revoir, Shosanna!
我要為部長準備下個約見
奴隸管工
法國奴隸的管工
我身為這項盛事的保安主管
不得不跟美慕小姐談談
談甚麼？
似乎有士兵質疑上校的命令
抑或是我過敏？
完全不是那回事
無人敢質疑上校的權力
不過，你先聲懾人
美慕小姐同我應該擔心嗎？
蘭達，小夥子沒有惡意
他只是患相思病
他說得對，你的確先聲懾人
你們不必擔心，我是保安主管
有責任同新場館的主人談談
有沒有嚐過這裡的蘋果酥？
沒有
不太差
你同兵哥怎樣結識？
兩件蘋果酥，每人一件
我要一杯咖啡，小姐嘛
一杯牛奶
小姐，你想解釋？
我兩天前才認識梭拉士兵
才聽過他的功績
他只是
戲院顧客，我們交談不過幾次
小姐，容我打岔
只是循例
不用焦慮
抱歉，我忘記叫忌廉
等一等
等忌廉來
艾曼妞可以叫你艾曼妞嗎？
可以
艾曼妞
我想了解
你這樣年輕，怎會擁有戲院？
請
如何？
正如我說，不太差
你正要解釋怎樣擁有戲院
戲院本來是我叔嬸的物業
甚麼名字？
尊皮亞、阿黛
現在在哪裡？
叔叔戰亂中死去
不幸啊
繼續
嬸嬸去年春季熱症病死
令人遺憾
你有個黑人僱員，對嗎？
對
法國人
叫馬素
戲院開張他就在這裡服務
只有他幫我手
做甚麼？
放映
他在行？
非常在行
那種工作或者適合他們
你懂操作放映機？
當然懂
我熟悉部長的脾氣
我相當肯定
他不希望盛會的成敗
全靠一個黑人
那麼
如果
盛會在你場館舉辦
即使你的黑人很擅長
你操作
放映機
可不可以？
可以
抽煙？
不是法國煙
是德國煙
我本來還有問題
奇怪，一時怎也想不起
必定不很重要
暫時不很重要
這戲院相當樸實
很有尊嚴，差點像教堂
但並非不可以修飾
可以從羅浮宮搬幾尊裸像來擺放
你喜歡《幸運兒》嗎？
我喜歡莉蓮夏菲
莉蓮夏菲！
不准對我提起那名字！
點算？
我們似乎要舉辦納粹片首映禮
我依然要問：“點算？”
我要同你商量
我不明白，商量甚麼？
趁戲院坐滿納粹，燒個清光
我不是那個意思
你是那個意思
我正想同你商量
你我可不可以
把戲院燒個清光？
可以，我們可以
美慕太太藏有350本硝酸菲林
我們甚至不用炸藥
對不對？
你指我們不用加添炸藥？
那年代35毫米硝酸菲林非常易燃
MALE NARRATOR.; At that time, 35 millimeter nitrate film was so flammable
連攜帶搭公車也禁止
that you couldn't even bring a reel onto a Streetcar.
不可以帶上車
Hey, you can't bring those here on a public vehicle.
﹣是菲林，是不是？﹣是
-They're films, ain't they? -Yes.
即是易燃物，下車
Then they're flammable. Go on, hop off.
硝酸菲林比紙張易燃三倍
MALE NARRATOR.; Because nitrate film burns three times faster than paper.
蘇珊娜藏有
Shosanna has a collection
350多本的硝酸影片菲林
of over 350 nitrate film prints.
我要在納粹之夜放火燒戲院
我知道
你不會
讓我單獨放火
你愛我，我愛你世上我只信你
我們不只放火
閣樓的拍戲器材可以用嗎？
攝影機可以用錄音機呢？
性能相當好
上星期錄過結他音樂，效果一流
為甚麼要拍戲器材？
親愛的馬素
我們要拍戲
專門給納粹看
第四章
戲院行動
這邊請，中尉
MAN: Right this way, Lieutenant.
希確斯上尉報到，將軍
Lieutenant Archie Hicox reporting, sir.
我是范尼治將軍，稍息
General Ed Fenech. At ease, Hicox.
喝東西嗎？
Drink?
可以的話，威士忌加水
If you offer me a scotch and plain water, I could drink a scotch and plain water.
好品味不要客氣，自己斟
That-a-boy, Lieutenant. Make it yourself like a good chap, will you?
酒在球裡
The bar is in the globe.
將軍要不要？
Something for yourself, sir?
威士忌，淨飲，不滲雜
Whiskey. Straight. No Junk in it.
根據記錄，你操流利德語
It says here that you speak German fluently.
帶外國口音
Like a KatzenJammer Kid.
﹣你戰前做甚麼？﹣影評人
-And your occupation before the war? -I'm a film critic.
﹣有甚麼作品？﹣例如吧，我替
List your accomplishments.
Well, sir, such as they are,
《電影與製作》寫影評與文章
I write reviews and articles for a publication called Films and Filmmakers,
出版過兩本書
and I've had two books published.
佩服不用謙虛，書名呢？
Impressive. Don't be modest, Lieutenant. What are their titles?
第一本
The first book was called
《視覺與心靈的藝術德國廿年代電影研究》
Art of the Eyes, the Heart and the Mind.; A Study of German Cinema in the '20S.
第二本《24格達文西》
And the second one was called Twenty-Four Frame da Vinci.
德國導演柏布斯其作品的索隱
It's a sub textual film criticism study of the work of German director G.W. Pabst.
﹣將軍，應該怎樣祝酒？﹣打倒
﹣希特拉﹣直至倒而不起
-Down with Hitler.  -All the way down, sir.
對
Yes.
熟悉德國第三帝國的電影嗎？
Are you familiar with German cinema under the Third Reich?
雖然這三年來未看過
Yes.
Obviously, I haven't seen any of the films made in the last three years,
﹣不過熟悉﹣解釋來聽
but I'm familiar with it.
Explain it to me.
甚麼？將軍
Pardon, sir?
我們要懂得第三帝國電影界情況
Well, this little escapade of ours requires a knowledge of the German film industry under the Third Reich.
才能執行行動戈培爾主掌影壇，情況怎樣？
Exeplain to me UFA under Goebbels.
戈培爾認為他所拍的電影
Goebbels considers the films he's making
開創德國電影新領域
to be the beginning of a new era in German cinema.
他認為不同廿年代
An alternative to what he considers
猶裔德國人的學術電影
the Jewish-German intellectual cinema of the '20s,
也不同猶太人控制的荷李活模式
and the Jewish-controlled dogma of Hollywood.
他的成績怎樣？
How's he doing?
很抱歉，你意思是？
Frightfully sorry, sir. Once again?
你說他要同猶太人鬥
You say he wants to take on the Jews at their own game.
例如說，同梅亞比較
Well, compared to, say, Louis B. Mayer,
﹣他的成績怎樣？﹣相當不錯
how's he doing?
Quite well, actually.
戈培爾掌權
Since Goebbels has taken over, film attendance has steadily risen in Germany over the last eight years.
八年來，觀眾人數穩步上升
但戈培爾不會同梅亞比
But Louis B. Mayer wouldn't be Goebbels' proper opposite number.
他會同大製片沙爾茲尼克比
I believe Goebbels sees himself closer to David O. Selznick.
告訴他吧
Brief him.
我們即將執行“戲院行動”
Lieutenant Hicox, at this point and time I'd like to brief you on Operation Kino.
三日後
Three days from now
戈培爾會在巴黎舉行首映禮
Joseph Goebbels is throwing a gala premiere of one of his new movies in Paris.
﹣甚麼電影？﹣《國家光榮》
-What film, sir?  -The motion picture is called Nation'S Pride.
出席這盛會的有
In attendance at this Joyous Germatic occasion
戈培爾、戈林、波文、大本營
will be Goebbels, Goring, Bormann, and most of the German High Command
包括黨衛軍、蓋世太保所有高官
including all high ranking officers of both the SS and the Gestapo,
還有納粹宣傳部的達官貴人
as well as luminaries of the Nazi propaganda film industry.
優秀民族的尋歡作樂？
The master race at play?
基本上，集壞蛋大全的一籃子
Basically, we have all our rotten eggs in one basket.
戲院行動的目的是
The objective of Operation Kino,
炸燬籃子
blow up the basket.
像隔年積雪一樣，融化於無形
And like the snows of yesteryear, gone from this earth.
好主意，將軍
Jolly good, sir.
一組美國特工已經深入敵區
An American Secret Service outfit that lives deep behind enemy lines
他們會協助你
will be your assist.
德軍叫他們辣手兵團
The Germans call them the Basterds.
辣手兵團，未聽過
The Basterds. Never heard of them.
街知巷聞就不是特工
Whole point of the Secret Service, old boy, you not hearing of them.
德軍聽過，被這班老美整得慘
But the Jerries have heard of them, because these Yanks have been them the devil.
你空降入法國，離巴黎24公里
You'll be dropped into France, about 24 kilometers outside of Paris.
辣手兵團會接你
The Basterds will be waiting for you.
你先去一條叫娜汀的村落
First thing, you'll go to a little village called Nadine.
娜汀村
進入村內一家酒館
In Nadine, there's a tavern called La Louisiane.
見我們的臥底，她會教你怎辦
There you'll rendezvous with our double agent. She'll take it from there.
她會帶你們出席首映禮
She's the one who is going to get you into the premiere.
你、她、兩個德國出生的辣手兵團
lt'll be you, her, and two German-born members of the Basterds.
她已經打點好一切
She's also made all the other arrangements you're going to need.
我怎樣認得她？
How will I know her?
難不倒你
I suspect that won't be too much trouble for you.
﹣臥底是韓瑪絲麥﹣韓瑪絲麥？
Your contact is Bridget von Hammersmark.
Bridget von Hammersmark?
德國女明星替英國效力？
(CHUCKLlNG) The German movie star is working for England?
已經兩年
Yes, for the last two years now.
戲院行動甚至可說是她的心血
One could even say that Operation Kino was her brainchild.
﹣哦﹣明白嗎？
-Indeed. -Got the gist?
明白了，巴黎將會很熱鬧
I think so, sir. Paris when it sizzles.
娜汀村
你沒有說會在地下室見面
You didn't say the goddamn rendezvous is in a fucking basement.
﹣我事前不知道﹣你說過是酒館
-I didn't know. -You said it was in a tavern.
﹣是酒館﹣地下室的酒館
-lt is a tavern. -Yeah, in a basement.
地下室內打鬥很困難
You know, fighting in a basement offers a lot of difficulties.
困難，因為是地下室
Number one being, you're fighting in a basement.
萬一她不在呢？
What if we go in there and she's not even there?
我們等
We wait.
放心，她是英國特務，必定出現
Don't worry. She's a British spy. She'll make the rendezvous.
﹣你叫史提傑茲？﹣對，上尉
Stiglitz, right?
That's right, sir.
聽說你刀法很好
I hear you're pretty good with that.
我們暫時不想生事
You know, we're not looking for trouble right now.
只是去同線人接頭，應該沒事
Simply making contact with our agent. Should be uneventful.
不過，萬一出事的話
However, the off chance I'm wrong, things prove eventful,
我們會不會鎮定？
I need to know we can all remain calm.
你不認為我鎮定？
I don't look calm to you?
你既然問起，我認為你鎮定
Well, now that you put it like that, I guess you do.
那個德國佬史提傑茲很少聲氣
This Jerry of yours, Stiglitz, not exactly the loquacious type, is he?
你要多聲氣的人？
Is that the kind of man you need? Loquacious type?
有理，中尉
Fair point, Lieutenant.
萬一出事的話，怎辦？
So you all get in trouble in there, what are we supposed to do?
怎樣應變？
Make bets on how it all comes out?
萬一出事的話
If we get into trouble, we can handle it.
你們要確保，沒有德國人
But if trouble does happen, we need you to make damn sure
甚至沒有法國人，走出地下室
no Germans, or French, for that matter, escape from that basement.
韓瑪絲麥身份敗露，任務完蛋
If Frau von Hammersmark's cover is compromised, the mission is kaput.
誰選擇那樣危險的地點會面？
Speaking of Frau von Hammersmark, whose idea was it for the death-trap rendezvous?
﹣她選擇﹣真有眼光
-She chose the spot.  -Isn't that just dandy?
她不是軍事專家，只是演員
Look, she's not a military strategist. She's just an actress.
誰也不會挑選在地下室打鬥
You don't got to be Stonewall Jackson to know you don't want to fight in a basement.
她不是挑選打鬥地點
She wasn't picking a place to fight.
只是挑選僻靜、沒有德軍的地點
She was picking a place isolated and without Germans.
我是男人
我是虛構的文學人物
我是美國人，這一點可以爭拗
完全不必爭拗
例如哈姆雷特
不是英國人，是丹麥人
這人物生於美國
好吧
瑪菲黛
氈酒？氈酒？
氈酒…氈酒…氈酒
五杯氈酒，麻煩你
如果我娶了太太
是否叫她做老婆？
是！
他猜中了
還可以問三次！
老沙特漢是我同胞？
是！
卡爾麥的筆下人物？
對！
那麼，你是誰？
我是阿帕奇猷長威尼圖！
對！
猜得好！
現在乾飲！
乾杯
立正！
各位好
請坐
等一等，我向新朋友道別
不用急，韓瑪絲麥小姐
慢慢，我們等
艾歷，這些朋友是來找我
麻煩你招待
韓瑪絲麥小姐，樂意遵命
各位
似乎小姐請飲酒
﹣飲甚麼？﹣威士忌
兩杯威士忌
﹣三杯威士忌﹣三杯威士忌，好
祝各位玩得開心
﹣你也是﹣謝謝
你的卡！
你說得對
讓我看看
成吉思汗！我絕不會猜到
你當然會！
哈囉
你好
歡迎歡迎
還以為這裡少德軍
通常是
那位上士的太太剛生了BB
他獲准同老友出營慶祝一晚
我們應該走
不要走
坐一坐
起碼飲一杯
我一直在酒吧等你們
未飲酒就走會引起懷疑
說得對，冷靜嘆杯威士忌吧
瑪菲黛
一起玩，頂替韓瑪絲麥小姐
她會樂於參加
我會翻譯並且保護她
不要擔心
我專炮製色狼
看吧
扯掉他的鼻
停手！
氈酒，各位舉杯
未繼續玩
先飲一杯
向我們朋友威廉祝酒
他的小BB
麥士
祝福麥士！
新情報
戲院改了
為甚麼？
不知道，但應該不成問題
新戲院比麗斯細得多
你們的炸藥會有雙倍殺傷力
另一項情報
非同小可
聽後不要太緊張
元首
請問
可不可以為我初生兒子簽名？
當然可以，威廉
這位英俊的上士今天做了父親
恭喜恭喜
謝謝
給小朋友起了名？
起了，叫麥士
麥士，美好的名字
謝謝，上尉
向小麥士致以至誠祝福
麥士現在不認識你，不過
我會帶他看盡你的電影
好
你的電影會陪他成長
這餐巾會掛在牆上
向全德國最偉大的女演員祝酒！
沒有德烈治！沒有瑞芬舒丹！只有韓瑪絲麥！
﹣乾杯！﹣乾杯！
繼續
韓瑪絲麥小姐，你為甚麼來法國？
不關你事！
上士
小姐或者容忍你的醉態
但我已經不耐煩
提醒你，上士你是士兵
這是軍官的桌子！
提議你不再騷擾小姐
回自己的桌子去
不好意思，上尉你口音很奇特
你是哪裡人？
你必定在發酒瘋
竟敢對上級軍官無禮！
上士
我要你們負責
建議你們約束朋友
否則麥士剛出世，他就鬧酒坐監
我可不可以發問？
像這位新任父親一樣
我也留意口音
像他一樣
我也覺得你奇怪
上尉，你是哪裡人？
少校，何必
我不是跟你談，慕尼黑中尉
也不是跟你談，法蘭克福中尉
我是跟來歷不明的上尉談
我在帕魯峰下一村落出生
﹣那山區？﹣對
我們家鄉都是這樣講話
有沒有看過瑞芬舒丹那齣戲？
﹣有﹣那麼你看過我
記不記得火炬滑雪那一幕？
記得
我們兄弟姐妹都參與做臨記
我弟弟很英俊
布柏斯導演拍他近鏡
少校先生，我雖然人微言輕
但可以保證上尉的話全部屬實
他從山腳打招呼
他們參與演出，弟弟遠比他英俊
你應該回你朋友那處
可以坐嗎？
隨便
好極！
難怪口音那樣特別
非常少有
你來做甚麼？
同這位美女喝酒
那是不在話下
我指來法國做甚麼
我認識駐守法國的德軍
所有駐法德軍？
凡是值得認識的
那就成問題了
我們從不自認有價值
認真說，來法國做甚麼？
陪伴小姐出席戈培爾部長的首映
你是韓瑪絲麥小姐的男伴
總得有人替她點煙
上尉是我男友，三位都是我客人
我們都是
多年老友
雖然女演員不願意認老
那麼
讓我向三位最幸運的男士乾杯
乾杯
瑞典女王
瑪塔哈麗
不得不承認
他們的遊戲相當有趣
不過，上尉，你說得對
軍官與士兵，上下有別
不過
既然大家都是軍官
都是高貴小姐的朋友
玩玩好嗎？
好，玩一鋪
好極
士兵
卡
謝謝
各位
遊戲的玩法
把名人的姓名寫在卡上
真假不論
可以寫孔子，也可以寫傅滿州
但必須是名人，不是姨媽姑姐
寫完，把卡面朝下放桌上
把卡推給你右邊的人
謝謝
你左邊的人把卡推向你
你撿起卡，不要看
舐一舐卡背
貼在前額上
寫！
寫
鐵金剛
馬可勃羅
柏布斯
碧姬荷妮
我開始，作為示範
我是德國人？
不是
我是美國人？
等一等，他去過
他分明不是生於美國
那麼我去過美國？
對
無意中去過？
對你來說不是
我的故鄉，很有異國情調？
是
即是說，不是森林，就是東方
憑直覺問一句“我是來自森林？”
是
現在可以問自己是真實、虛構
但太容易了，所以暫時不問
好
我的故鄉在森林
我去過美國
但並不是無意中去
意思是別人令你去
當我
從森林去美國
我乘船去？
對
我是被逼去？
船上，我戴上枷鎖？
對
去到美國，戴枷鎖給人看？
我是美國的黑奴？
不是
我必定是鐵金剛
猜得好！
佩服！
我既然猜中，大家要乾杯
乾杯
下個輪到誰？
少校
不好意思，我們四個人是
久未見的老友
少校
不要見怪
你在打擾了
我不敢苟同
小姐嫌我打擾我才算打擾
韓瑪絲麥小姐
我有沒有打擾？
料也沒有
只有上尉才無視我的魅力
只是講笑
當然是打擾了
我請各位飲一瓶酒，然後告辭
艾歷有瓶33年威士忌
正宗蘇格蘭名產
各位，賞面嗎？
你很客氣，少校
艾歷！33年老威，新酒杯！
不要讓劣酒污染佳釀
幾多隻杯？
﹣五隻﹣我不要
蘇格蘭同我無緣
我繼續喝香檳
三隻
韓瑪絲麥小姐
謝謝
德意志帝國萬歲！
無謂再做戲
有沒有聽到？
我那把華瑟的聲音
對準你的睪丸
為甚麼用槍指我睪丸？
因為你露出馬腳
你不比威士忌更德國
﹣少校﹣收聲，賤人
你想說甚麼？
我想說的是彼此彼此
我一早已經用槍瞄準你波子
我也是
這樣近距離，好難射歪
情形有點棘手
少校，你要站起來
同我們出外
不可以，我不同意
很遺憾
你知我知，上尉
無論怎樣收科
你我都走不掉
威廉同他的朋友也倒楣
你們想活，也要殺死他們
似乎小麥士一出世就要做孤兒
多麼可悲
既然是這樣
Well, if this is it, old boy,
希望你不介意我臨終說母語
I hope you don't mind if I go out speaking the King's.
請隨便，上尉
By all means, Captain.
美酒當前，不呷一口
There's a special rung in hell reserved for people who waste good Scotch.
死也死得冤枉
Seeing as I may be rapping on the door momentarily,
無可否認認真香醇，少校
damn good stuff, sir.
關於我們
Now, about this pickle
這濕滯處境
we find ourselves in.
似乎只有一件事你可以做
It would appear there's only one thing left for you to do.
甚麼事？
And what would that be?
﹣史提傑茲﹣向你納粹波子講聲拜拜
-Stiglitz.  -Say auf wiederSehen to your Nazi balls.
外面的人，是誰？
You outside. Who are you?
英國人？美國人？
British? American?
甚麼人？
What?
美國人
ALDO: We're American.
你呢？
What are you?
德國人呀，死蠢
I'm a German, you idiot.
德國人，英語不錯
ALDO: Speak English pretty good for a German.
同意
I agree.
我們談談
So let's talk.
好，談吧
ALDO: Okay, talk.
我做了爸爸
I'm a father.
我BB今日在法蘭克福出世
My baby was born today. In Frankfurt.
五小時前
Five hours ago.
名叫麥士我們來飲酒慶祝
His name is Max. We were in here drinking, celebrating.
他們進來開槍殺人，不關我事！
They're the ones that came in shooting and killing. It's not my fault!
得！不關你事
ALDO: Okay! It wasn't your fault.
你叫甚麼？
What's your name, soldier?
威廉
Wilhelm.
我們有沒有活口？
Now, is there anybody alive on our side?
﹣沒有﹣我未死！
No.
I'm alive!
是誰？
ALDO: Who's that?
女人是你們的人？
Is the girl on your side?
哪個女人？
ALDO: Which girl?
還有誰？韓瑪絲麥
Who do you think? Von Hammersmark.
對，是我們的人
ALDO: Yeah, she's ours.
她沒事？
ALDO: Is she okay?
威廉！
ALDO: Wilhelm!
中了槍
She's been shot.
但死不去
But she's alive.
好吧，威廉
ALDO: Okay, Wilhelm.
你我來個交易怎樣？
What do you say we make us a deal?
你叫甚麼？
What's your name?
艾杜
Aldo.
威廉，這樣交易
Okay, Wilhelm, here's my deal.
你讓我下來，接走女人
You let me and one of my men come down there and take the girl away.
你不開槍，我不開槍
No guns. No guns me, no guns you.
我帶走女人，簡單得很
And we take the girl and leave. It's that simple, Willi.
你走你路，我過我橋
You go your way, we go ours.
小麥士不用做孤兒
And little Max gets to grow up playing catch with his daddy.
怎樣？有沒有交易？
So what do you say, Willi? We got us a deal?
艾杜
Aldo.
我在這裡，阿威
ALDO: I'm here, Willi.
我想信你
I want to trust you.
不過…
怎樣信得過？
But how can l?
你有甚麼選擇？
ALDO: What choice you got, son?
好吧
Okay, okay.
艾杜
Aldo,
我信你
I'm going to trust you.
下來
Come down.
為甚麼槍指指？我們有交易
Hey, Willi, what's with the machine gun? I thought we had us a deal?
我們有交易，帶女子走吧
We still have a deal. Now, get the girl and go.
且慢
Not so fast.
講明我信你，你信我
We only got a deal, we trust each other.
不是你指我，我指你
And a Mexican standoff ain't trust.
我指你，你沒有指我
You need guns on me for it to be a Mexican standoff.
你開槍，射死我們
You got guns on us. You decide to shoot, we're dead.
他們從上面掟手榴彈，炸死你
Up top, they got grenades. They drop them down here, you're dead.
即是你指我，我指你
That's a Mexican standoff, and that was not the deal.
你不信我，我不信你
No trust, no deal.
好吧，艾杜
All right, Aldo.
好
Fine.
帶走反骨賤人，免得我眼冤
just take that fucking traitor, and get her out of my sight.
等一等，醫生叫他去陪狗玩
Not so goddamn fast, doc.
Tell him to go play with his dogs.
未拔子彈，先問幾句
Before we yank that slug out you, you need to answer a few questions.
問甚麼？
Few questions about what?
我死了三個人
About I got three men dead back there.
經過是怎樣？說來聽
Why don't you try telling us what the fuck happened?
蓋世太保識穿英國人假冒
The British officer blew his German act and the Gestapo major saw it.
未說下去之前
Before we get into who shot John,
為甚麼選擇有納粹的地下室？
why'd you invite my men to a rendezvous in a basement with a bunch of Nazis?
你沒有在場
I can see since you didn't see what happened inside,
難怪覺得奇怪
that the Nazis being there must look odd.
有更適合的形容詞
Yeah, we got a word for that kind of odd in English.
叫可疑
It's called suspicious.
大家冷靜點
Everybody needs to calm down.
不要胡思亂想
You're letting your imagination get the better of you.
你見過上士阿威
You met the sergeant yourself. Willi.
記得吧？
You remember him, don't you?
記得
Yeah, I remember him.
他太太今晚剛剛生了BB
他做了爸爸！
He had just become a father!
長官批准他同老友出來慶祝
His commanding officer gave him and his mates the night off to celebrate.
德軍在場不是我的圈套，就是註定劫數
The Germans being there was either a trap set by me or a tragic coincidence.
不可能兩者都是
It couldn't be both.
怎樣開起槍來？
How'd the shooting start?
英國人露出馬腳
The Englishman gave himself away.
怎樣露？
How'd he do that?
他叫三隻杯
He ordered three glasses.
我們叫隻三杯
We order three glasses.
德國的三
That's the German three.
其他手勢看來怪
The other looks odd.
德軍察覺到
Germans would and did notice it.
沒有發生這件事
Okay, let's pretend there were no Germans
見面順利的話
and everything went exactly the way it was supposed to.
下一步怎樣？
What was the next step?
禮服
Tuxedos.
首映禮有大批軍官
To get them into the premiere wearing military uniforms
他們穿軍服去，等於自殺
with all the military there would've been suicide.
扮穿禮服，扮電影界的人
But going as members of the German film industry,
可以混入人群
they wear tuxedos and fit in with everybody else.
我安排了裁縫今晚試衫
I arranged for the tailor to fit three tuxedos tonight.
你怎樣帶他們入場？
How'd you intend to get them in that premiere?
遞手袋來
Hand me my purse.
希確斯上尉是我男伴
Lieutenant Hicox was going as my escort.
其他兩人是攝影師與助手
The other two were going as a German cameraman and his assistant.
你還能帶我們入場嗎？
You still get us in that premiere?
你德語流利？不是
You speak German better than your friends? No.
我有沒有中槍？有！
Have I been shot? Yes!
我沒法踏紅地氈，出風頭
I don't see me tripping the light fantaStique up a red carpet anytime soon.
尤其在明晚
Least of all, by tomorrow night.
不過，你們有所不知
However, there's something you don't know.
戲院行動有兩點變化
There've been two recent developments regarding Operation Kino.
第一點首映由麗斯改為細得多的戲院
One, the venue has been changed from The Ritz to a much smaller venue.
臨時變陣？不符合德國人性格
Enormous change at the last minute? That's not very Germatic.
為甚麼戈培爾這樣出位？
Why the hell is Goebbels doing stuff so damn peculiar?
很可能同第二點有關
It probably has something to do with the second development.
即是？
Which is?
元首出席首映《國家光榮》
Der Fuhrer is attending the premiere.
在巴黎的首映禮
我再考慮過
近幾星期的戰局
美軍登陸沙灘
我愈來愈覺得
這個叫梭拉的士兵
做出很能鼓舞人心的事情
我認為
我出席的話，會有意義
還得了！
Fuck a duck!
你有甚麼打算？
What are you thinking?
我打算隊冧希特拉
I'm thinking getting a whack at planting old Uncle Adolf
去贈他們慶
makes this horse a different color.
意思是？
What is that supposed to mean?
意思是，你帶我們進場
It means you getting us in that premiere.
我很可能廢了這條腿
I'm probably going to end up losing this leg.
連演藝事業也要收檔
Bye-bye, acting career. Fun while it lasted.
你還要我行紅地氈？
How do you expect me to walk the red carpet?
狗醫會替你拔子彈
Doggy doc's going to dig that slug out your gam.
他會替你打石膏
He's going to wrap it up in a cast,
你會說你爬山摔斷腿
and you got a good how-I-broke-my-leg-mountain-climbing story.
德國人都好爬山，對嗎？
That's German, ain't it? You all like climbing mountains, don't you?
我不好，我好煙好酒好美食
I don't. I like smoking, drinking and ordering in restaurants.
但我明白你用意
But I see your point.
我們會打嗎啡打到你麻木
We fill you up with morphine till it's coming out your ears
打到你可以拐上紅地氈
and just limp your little ass up that rouge carpet.
我知道問得多餘
I know this is a silly question before I ask it,
但你們美國人除了英語還懂甚麼語？
but can you Americans speak any other language than English?
我倆都懂幾句意大利話
We both speak a little Italian.
必定是非常有限公司
With an atrocious accent, no doubt.
但並非完全行不通
But that doesn't exactly kill us in the crib.
德國人不太懂意大利話
Germans don't have a good ear for Italian.
你打算咿咿哦哦混過關？
So you mumble Italian and brazen through it. ls that the plan?
差不多
That's about it.
好橋
That sounds good.
屎橋，但還可以怎樣？回家？
It sounds like shit. What else are we going to do? Go home?
是好橋
No, that sounds good.
你們不穿崩，我可以帶你們進場
If you don't blow it, with that, I can get you in the building.
誰扮誰？
Who does what?
我最懂意語，我扮你男伴
Well, I speak the most Italian, so I'll be your escort.
當奴威茲懂較少，扮攝影師
Donowitz speaks second most, so he'll be your Italian cameraman.
奧馬懂最少，扮阿當助手
Omar, third most. He'll be Donny's assistant.
我完全不懂
I don't speak Italian.
所以你懂最少，盡量收嗲好了
Like I said, third best.
Just keep your fucking mouth shut.
不如現在開始練吧
In fact, why don't you start practicing right now?
原來你紮了職
升了中尉
作反也可以作到紮職，服你
那個人
叫域基
奧地利猶太人，納粹興起
他見勢色不對，移民了去美國
辣手兵團有兩人德國出世
扮德軍，偷襲德軍
你們來做甚麼？
這情形不像偷襲
奇怪
似乎欠缺一個人
一個時髦的人
大家出去！
“向小麥士致以至誠祝福”
韓瑪絲麥
第五章
巨大面孔的復仇
《國家光榮》首映禮之夜
記住說英語
Yes.
開拍
誰肯替我們沖曬？
只有我們那種自殺狂才肯
即使有人肯
哪裡找有聲35毫米底片？
我們找個能夠沖曬的人
逼他沖曬
以死去威逼
抓賤種來！頭放桌上
你不沖曬
我劈斷你的走狗頭
我不是走狗
馬素，你認識他妻兒？
認識
我們替人民殺死走狗
再去滅他們口
夏文戈林
贊寧斯，戒指呢？
給大家看吧
這是我所頒的最高藝術榮譽
﹣博士，我很榮幸﹣你實至名歸
今日首映後，有新候選人
艾曼妞
我來介紹，世上最偉大演員
贊寧斯
你的戲院很漂亮
謝謝你，夏文
韓瑪絲麥小姐
蘭達上校，多年不見
風采依然啊
玉腿發生甚麼事？
在影壇上踢人屁股踢傷了？
不要口花花
不知幾多女子被你氹上手
究竟甚麼事？
我不自量力
學人爬山
這是結果
爬山？
你爬山爬傷腿？
信不信由你，是實情
我不是幸災樂禍
不過…爬山？
為甚麼
突然有這股傻勁？
以後不會再爬，可以保證
石膏是剛剛打
幾時爬？昨晚？
眼光奇準啊，上校
昨天早上
巴黎哪個山？
只是作弄你
你也知我喜歡搗蛋
三名英偉的男伴是誰？
不好意思，他們不懂德語
是我意大利的朋友
意大利特技高手高路米
天才攝影師馬格里提
攝影助手狄高高
我老朋友黨衛軍的蘭達上校
哈囉
各位好
我們的紅星文化的明珠
她的朋友當然要由我保護了
謝謝
我說得正確嗎？
哎…正確
請再說一次
甚麼？再說？
再說？
再說貴姓大名
我想聽聽動聽的意大利話！
而你是？
兩位攝影師要找座位
讓我看看門票
你是大明星為朋友撲飛
大概不難
0023與0024
應該不難找到，再見
馬田波曼希特拉心腹波曼
犀利囉，十足大明星
我要下去應酬匈奴豬玀
再溫習一次
第一本片用第一號機
第二本片
第二號機
第三本片在捲軸上
第四本片準備就緒
狙擊槍戰的大場面
在第三本中間開始
我們的菲林在第四本
第三本播到臨尾
下樓去把出口上鎖
然後站在銀幕背後，我發訊號
你點火
各位請坐
電影即將放映
各位請坐，電影即將放映
稍後見
且慢
一杯香檳
為《國家光榮》乾杯
可不可以私下跟你說幾句？
當然可以
失陪
請坐
可以嗎？
美慕小姐借出
她的辦公室給我用
讓我看看你的腳
甚麼？
腳放在我膝上
你令我不好意思
請伸手入我外套右口袋
取出裡面的物件
可以嗎？
有句俗語“有幾大隻腳，著幾大隻鞋”
What's that American expression?
"If the shoe fits, you must wear it."
又怎樣？上校
白色晚禮服的男人
仆街、死仆街！
ALDO: Fucking shithead. Faggot fuck. Fuck you!
統統仆街
Bunch of shithead fuck.
你都仆街
Fuck you, too!
納粹賤種！不要碰我
Goddamn Nazi farts, sons of bitches! Get your hands off me.
死潤腸！躝開！
聰明
我報告了元首觀眾已經入座
他應該隨時抵達
謝謝你，蘭達
賤格雜種…
放手
失敬了，閣下是艾杜中尉？
As Stanley said to Livingstone
Lieutenant Aldo Raine, I presume?
你都算作惡得太久了
You've had a nice long run, Aldo.
現在落入黨衛軍手上
Alas, you're now in the hands of the SS.
更加落入我的手上
My hands to be exact.
大家不知多渴望炮製你
And they've been waiting a long time to touch you.
你現在怕了
Caught you flinching.
試試再碰我啦，潤腸
ALDO: Touch me again, Kraut-burger.
﹣烏提域治？﹣是你嗎？中尉
Utivich?
Is that you, Lieutenant?
ALDO: Yeah.
阿當怎樣？
UTlVlCH: Do you know what happened to Donny?
奧馬呢？
Omar?
﹣那女人呢？﹣不知道
The woman?
No, I do not.
告訴我，你我易地而處的話
Tell me, Aldo, if I were sitting where you're sitting,
你會放過我嗎？
would you show me mercy?
不會
Nope.
有句俗語甚麼“輪流轉”？
What is that English expression about shoes and feet?
“風水輪流轉”我也是那樣想
"Looks like the shoe is on the other foot." Yeah, I was just thinking that.
你們出去
保持戒備
你是生番艾杜
So you're Aldo the Apache.
﹣你是猶太獵手﹣我是偵探
So you're The Jew Hunter.
I'm a detective.
一流偵探
A damn good detective.
專門狩獵人
Finding people is my specialty,
當然，我是替納粹黨獵人
so naturally, I worked for the Nazis finding people.
既獵猶太人，也獵其他人
And, yes, some of them were Jews. But Jew Hunter?
但大家只我叫猶太獵手
just a name that stuck.
不得不承認，易記易叫
Well, you do have to admit, it is catchy.
敵人要起你花名，由你不得
Do you control the nicknames your enemies bestow on you?
生番艾杜、矮仔
Aldo the Apache and the Little Man?
矮仔？甚麼意思？
What do you mean the Little Man?
德軍替你起的花名
Germans' nickname for you.
德軍叫我做矮仔？
The Germans' nickname for me is the Little Man?
你其實不太矮，我也有點意外
And as if to make my point, I'm a little surprised how tall you were in real life.
雖然矮
I mean, you're a little fellow, but not circus-midget little,
但未矮過矮冬瓜
as your reputation would suggest.
我的手下呢？
Where's my men?
韓瑪絲麥呢？
Where's Bridget von Hammersmark?
她可以說是應有此報
Well, let's just say, she got what she deserved.
你收買韓瑪絲麥那種貨色
And when you purchase friends like Bridget von Hammersmark,
一分錢，一分貨
you get what you pay for.
至於兩件冒牌意大利貨當奴威茲上士、奧馬士兵…
你怎知道我們姓名？
How you know our names?
艾杜中尉
Lieutenant Aldo,
你以為我沒有盤問
if you don't think I wouldn't interrogate
每個被你刻標記的生還軍人
every single one of your swastika-marked survivors,
你我就不是識英雄重英雄了
we simply aren't operating on the level of mutual respect I assumed.
大概不是
No, I guess not.
說回你兩個破壞份子
Well, back to the whereabouts of your two Italian saboteurs.
這一刻
As of this moment,
奧馬同當奴威茲應該依然安坐戲院席上
both Omar and Donowitz should be sitting in the very seats we left them in.
0023、0024號位，沒有記錯的話
Double-zero 23 and double-zero 24, if my memory serves.
小腿綁著炸藥，隨時爆炸
Explosives still around their ankles, still ready to explode.
而你的任務或稱你的恐怖活動
And your mission, some would call a terrorist plot,
這一刻，依然可以實行
as of this moment, is still a go.
刺激，跟著呢？神奇老鼠出現？
That's a pretty exciting story. What's next? Eliza on Ice?
只要我拎起電話
all I have to do is pick up this phone right here, inform the cinema, and your plan is kaput.
通知戲院，你的計劃玩完
萬一他們未死萬一還在戲院內，我強調萬一
If they're still here, and if they're still alive
and that's one big if,
你們未走近，他們已經引爆
there ain't no way you're going to take them boys without setting off them bombs.
可以肯定
I have no doubt.
會炸死幾個德國人首映夜會腰斬
And, yes, some Germans will die. Yes, it will ruin the evening.
戈培爾會咬牙切齒
And, yes, Goebbels will be very, very, very mad at you
for what you've done to his big night.
但你炸不死希特拉
But you won't get Hitler, you won't get Goebbels,
炸不死戈培爾、戈林、波曼
you won't get Goring, and you won't get Bormann.
炸死這四人，才能結束戰事
And you need all four to end the war.
但我不拎起電話的話
But if I don't pick up this phone right here,
你很可能炸死四人
you may very well get all four.
你炸死四人，結束戰爭
And if you get all four, you end the war
今晚就結束
tonight.
那麼，兩位
So, gentlemen,
今晚有沒有可能結束戰事呢？
let's discuss the prospect of ending the war tonight.
希特拉
So, the way I see it,
是死是活，完全視乎我的反應
since Hitler's death or possible rescue rests solely on my reaction,
我袖手旁觀，他死
if I do nothing,
所以，我比你們更能要他命同意嗎？
it's as if I'm causing his death even more than yourselves. Wouldn't you agree?
大概同意
I guess so.
你呢？烏提域治
How about you, Utivich?
我也同意
I guess so, too.
兩位，我無意
Gentlemen, I have no intention of killing Hitler and killing Goebbels and killing Goring and killing Bormann,
殺死納粹四大天王更加無意
隻手為盟軍打勝世界大戰
not to mention winning the war single-handedly for the Allies,
而戰後接受猶太人審判
only later to find myself standing before a Jewish tribunal.
你們想今晚取勝
If you want to win the war tonight,
我們要來一宗交易
we have to make a deal.
甚麼交易？
What kind of deal?
這宗交易，你未有資格做主
The kind you wouldn't have the authority to make.
但你必定有指揮官指揮官必定是
However, I'm sure this mission of yours has a commanding officer.
一名將軍
A general.
我猜是
戰略局的將軍
OSS would be my guess.
That's a bingo!
那是猜中！
是不是那樣說？
Is that the way you say it? "That's a bingo."
只用說：“猜中”
You just say, "Bingo."
猜中！過癮
Bingo! How fun.
話題扯開了說到哪裡？交易
But I digress. Where were we? Yeah! Make a deal.
那處，有一具性能良好的通訊機
Over there is a very capable two-way radio and sitting behind it
有一個能力優越的操作員夏文
is a more than capable radio operator named Hermann.
我有一列條件
Get me someone on the other end of that radio
姑且稱為投降條件吧
with the power of the pen to authorize my,
你替我接通一位有資格接受
let's call it, the terms of my conditional surrender.
這些條件的將軍吧
If that tastes better going down.
我家鄉的人
哪處？
Yeah? Where is that exactly?
田納西州梅納德維市
Maynardville, Tennessee.
我釀製過私酒
I've done my share of bootlegging.
釀製私酒是犯法行為
Up there, if you engage in what the federal government calls illegal activity,
但為了養家，沒法
but what we call just a man trying to make a living for his family, selling moonshine liquor
我們這些做非法生意的人
it behooves oneself to keep his wits.
最緊要眉精眼企我們知道世事
Long story short, we hear a story too good to be true,
沒有那樣著數
it ain't.
我是你，我也有那樣的想法
Sitting in your chair, I would probably say the same thing,
絕大多數，那是正確的想法
and 999.999 times out of a million, you would be correct.
但史冊中，會偶然機緣巧合
But in the pages of history, every once in a while,
出現神來之筆
fate reaches out and extends its hand.
今晚的歷史，應該怎樣寫？
What shall the history books read?
MAN.; I implore you. we must destroy that tower.
MAN.; The tower Stands!
香口膠
時間到
我去鎖出口，到銀幕背後準備
我要軍事史記錄著
HANS: So when the military history of this night is written,
我參與今晚的戲院行動
it will be recorded that I was part of Operation Kino
我從始就是雙重間諜
from the very beginning as a double agent.
我作為黨衛軍上校的一切作為
Anything I've done in my guise as an SS Colonel
都是經過戰略局許可
was sanctioned by the OSS as a necessary evil
都是不得已，為了掩飾身份
to establish my cover with the Germans.
是我把艾杜中尉的炸藥
And it was my placement of Lieutenant Raine's dynamite
放在希特拉、戈座下，確保他們歸西
in Hitler and Goebbels' opera box that assured their demise.
我報告了元首觀眾已經入座
他應該隨時抵達
謝謝你，蘭達
還有，我確實放了炸藥
By the way, that last part is actually true.
我要享有與官階相符的充分退休金與福利
I want my full military pension and benefits under my proper rank.
我推翻納粹，立下豐功偉績
I want to receive the Congressional Medal of Honor
我要獲頒國會榮譽勳章
for my invaluable assistance in the toppling of the Third Reich.
我要所有戲院行動的成員
In fact, I want all the members of Operation Kino
也獲頒國會榮譽勳章
to receive the Congressional Medal of Honor.
不消說，我要得到十足公民權
Full citizenship for myself. Well, that goes without saying.
我要美國政府替我
And I would like the United States of America
在南塔克特島，購買物業
to purchase property for me on Nantucket lsland
酬答我迅雷不及掩耳神速剷除暴政
as a reward for all the countless lives I've saved
拯救萬民於水深火熱中
by bringing the tyranny of the National Socialist Party
記下來了？
to a swifter-than-imagined end. Do you have all that, sir?
我也期待同你見面，將軍
I look forward to seeing you face to face as well, sir.
艾杜中尉？在這裡
Lieutenant Raine? Right here.
是，將軍
Yes, sir.
上校會把你倆當作戰俘押上車
GENERAL.; Colonel Landa will put you and Private Utivich in a truck as priSonerS.
他同通訊員載你倆到我軍地區
Then he and his radio operator will get in the truck and drive to our lines.
一抵達，上校兩人會向你投降
Upon crossing our lines, Colonel Landa and his man will surrender to you.
你立即把他們
You will then take over driving of the truck
載來向我匯報，明白嗎？
and bring them straight to me for debriefing.
Is that clear, Lieutenant?
明白，將軍
Yes, sir.
通話完畢
Over and out.
戈培爾博士，我想出一出去
明白，小夥子去吧，散場見
誰？
法德烈！
弊
你是戲院老闆嗎？我要回水
男主角的演技好差
你來做甚麼？
探你嘛
你看不出我多忙？
讓我幫手吧
不要胡鬧，你不可以來
你的首映，應該去陪嘉賓
一般來說，你說得對
其他電影
我會正襟危坐，看畢全場
不過，這齣戲
改編自我的作戰事蹟
尤其是我大開殺戒的事蹟
現在上映的場面
我更不想看
﹣抱歉，不過…﹣於是
我決定上來
努力去煩你
從你表情看來，我依然煩得到
你習慣了納粹的奉承
忘記了“不”字的意思？
你不可以來！
走吧！
你撞痛我
你還有感覺，那是好事
即使是痛的感覺
我不是可以揮之則去的人
有三百多具屍體證實不可以！
我這樣為你
你不把我放在眼內，是嫌命長！
鎖門
甚麼？
我們時間無多
甚麼時間？
算了！
不…等一等
你要我…鎖門？
好長氣呀，鎖啦
我先殺一個，你衝上來殺另一個
When I kill that guy, you got 30 feet to get to that guard.
﹣辦得到嗎？﹣不可以辦不到
Can you do it?
I have to.
香檳？
Champagne?
精彩，簡直精彩！
你的代表作
過獎了，元首
過獎
誰可以給德國送訊息？
who wantS to send a message to Germany?
我有信息送給德國
I have a message for Germany.
你們個個死到臨頭
That you are all going to die.
放肆！停播！
關放映機！
看清看楚這張面孔吧我就是送你們歸西的猶太人！
And I want you to look deep into the face of the Jew who's going to do it!
不是我的電影！
馬素，放火
Marcel, burn it down.
是，蘇珊娜
Oui, Shosanna.
我叫戴蘇珊娜
My name iS Shosanna Dreyfus,
這張面孔
and this is the face
是報仇的猶太人
of Jewish vengeance.
已經駛到美軍區，上校
好極，夏文
夏文，解手銬
我正式向你投降，艾杜中尉
I'm officially surrendering myself over to you, Lieutenant Raine.
我們是你的戰俘
We're your prisoners.
我把刀？
How about my knife?
非常感謝，上校
Thank you very much, Colonel.
把上校雙手反鎖
Utivich, cuff the Colonel's hands behind his back.
真有必要嗎？
Is that really necessary?
我這個人很注重門面
I'm a slave to appearances.
割夏文頭皮
Scalp Hermann.
發神經嗎？
Are you mad?
搞甚麼？
What have you done?
你的將軍保證過他活命！
I made a deal with your general for that man's life!
對，但他們不在乎他，只要你
Yeah, they made that deal. But they don't give a fuck about him. They need you.
他們會槍斃你！
You'll be shot for this!
不會槍斃，最多臭罵一頓我捱慣罵
Nah, I don't think so. More like chewed out. I've been chewed out before.
我們聽到你同將軍的交易
You know, Utivich and myself heard that deal you made with the brass.
今晚結束戰爭？
End the war tonight?
換上我，我會交易
I'd make that deal.
你呢？烏提域治
How about you, Utivich? You make that deal?
﹣我也會﹣物超所值嘛
I'd make that deal.
I don't blame you. Damn good deal.
你為自己鋪好後路
And that pretty little nest you feathered for yourself.
你既然願意油炸總司令
Well, if you're willing to barbecue the whole High Command,
這宗交易大概值得考慮
I suppose that's worth certain considerations.
但我想問一句
But I do have one question.
你入住南塔克特島的豪宅
When you get to your little place on Nantucket Island,
大概會脫掉威風凜凜的黨衛軍服
I imagine you are going to take off that handsome-looking SS uniform of yours.
是不是？
Ain't you?
我也認為會
That's what I thought.
那我可不能接受
Now, that I can't abide.
烏提域治，你能接受嗎？
How about you, Utivich, can you abide it?
絕對不能，中尉
Not one damn bit, sir.
由我話事的話
I mean, if I had my way,
我要你穿臭軍服穿足一生一世
you'd wear that goddamn uniform for the rest of your pecker-sucking life.
不過，那是不切實際
But I'm aware that ain't practical.
你遲早會脫掉
I mean, at some point, you're going to have to take it off.
於是
So,
我要給你一件你脫不掉的東西
I'm going to give you a little something you can't take off.
烏提域治？
You know something, Utivich?
這或者是我曠世之作
I think this just might be my masterpiece.
Cantonese